Things here
这里的东西
if i don't say
如果我不说
no one will know
没有人会知道
Said today
今天说
But it’s not for people to know
但这不是为了让人们知道
just because of
只是因为
This Luzhai is the most deserted house in Qingxian County.
这鹿寨是青县最荒废的房子。
No women, no children
没有女人，没有孩子
Not even a dog
连狗都没有
In today’s house
今天的家里
Only Lu Yuanbao
Only Lu Yuanbao
Just a bunch of servants
只是一群仆人
fuck the young master
他妈的 少爷
Who do I think I am?
我以为我是谁？
Scared me
吓死我了
Should be scared to death
应该被吓死
If it weren't for me, Lu Zhi
如果不是我，卢植
I'll meet you with someone else
我会和其他人一起去见你
You, Chen Wang, will definitely receive a severe beating.
你陈旺肯定会被狠狠打一顿的。
Master, please forgive me.
师父，请原谅我。
Didn't you say you are not allowed to call me "Master"?
你不是说不许叫我“师父”吗？
Yes Yes
是的是的
I ask you
我问你
Did you gamble all night again yesterday?
昨天你又赌了一整夜吗？
small bet small bet
小赌小赌
Where did you get that ladder?
你从哪里得到那个梯子？
This ladder
这个梯子
I hid it outside the courtyard wall yesterday
昨天我把它藏在院墙外面了
Just for this morning
只为了今天早上
Able to climb over the wall and get in
能够翻墙进去
I thought I was unaware of the ghosts
我以为我对鬼魂一无所知
I didn't expect to meet you
我没想到会遇见你
Meeting me is your creation
遇见我是你的创造
It just so happened that I was on duty last night
刚好我昨晚值班
I ask you
我问你
you last night
你昨晚
Did he lose again and lose everything?
难道他又输了，失去了一切？
I've been having bad luck lately
我最近运气不好
I won’t advise you anymore
我不会再给你建议
It's useless to persuade
说服是没有用的
Why don't you secretly go to the woodshed to catch up on your sleep?
何不偷偷去柴房补觉呢？
I'll call you if something happens
如果有事我会打电话给你
What should you do?
你该怎么办？
You just spent the night on night duty.
你刚刚值夜班。
Then I'll go to the woodshed to catch up on my sleep in the afternoon.
然后下午我就去柴房补觉。
If anything happens, call me again
如果有什么事请再给我打电话
Thank you, Mr. Qian
谢谢钱先生
Can not be done
无法完成
I still have some shopping errands to do today.
我今天还有一些购物任务要做。
give me list
给我清单
I'll help you do it
我会帮你做的
prescription
处方
you feel unwell
你感觉不舒服
Actually, I went to gamble yesterday
其实我昨天去赌博了
Not for fun
不是为了好玩
It's because I don't have enough money to get medicine.
因为我没有足够的钱买药。
I wanted to win some money
我想赢一些钱
Buying medicine for my mother
给妈妈买药
result
结果
Your mother is sick
你妈妈病了
old disease root
老病根
Did it again
又那么做了
fuck the young master
他妈的 少爷
what are you doing
你在干什么
I'll go help your mother get some medicine first.
我先去帮你妈妈拿点药。
Let's go do the shopping again
我们再去买东西吧
The drug store isn't open yet
药店还没开门
The door to the drugstore is always open at your request.
药店的大门随时根据您的要求敞开。
Besides, I’m going to our own pharmacy.
另外，我要去我们自己的药房。
Your prescriptions were all prescribed the day before yesterday.
你的药方都是前天开的。
Been delayed for two days
延误了两天
Don't follow me
别跟着我
I can go by myself
我可以自己去
Lu Zhi is a good boy
陆智是个好孩子
Up and down the Lu family
陆家上下
Who doesn’t love Lu Zhi?
谁不爱卢植？
but
但
The person who dotes on him the most is member Lu Yuanbao
最宠他的人是成员陆元宝
He even sent him to private school
还送他去私立学校
This sentence means
这句话的意思是
Zengzi said
Zengzi said
There are rumors outside
外界有传言
Yuan Wai recognized Lu Zhi as his godson
元外认卢植为干儿子
The lifeblood of the country with a radius of hundreds of miles
方圆百里国家的命脉
You can trust him
你可以相信他
servant of the house
仆人
I also call him privately
我也私下打电话给他
fuck the young master
他妈的 少爷
Is such a person considered a gentleman?
这样的人还算绅士吗？
Such a person is a gentleman
这样的人就是君子
Then recite
然后背诵
Zengzi said
Zengzi said
A scholar cannot be without Hongyi
学者不可无弘毅
stop
停止
What’s the meaning of this Hongyi?
这个弘毅是什么意思？
Hirosha Daiya
广社大哉
The perseverant is strong
坚持的人是坚强的
gentlemen
先生们
But there is a result
但有一个结果
Each of the four characters has its own merits
四个角色各有各的优点
The first three paintings are even more indistinguishable
前三幅画更是难以区分
But this last one
但这最后一张
Looks different
看起来不一样
Sir, take it seriously
先生，请认真对待
Sir, have you ever made fun of me?
先生，您曾经取笑过我吗？
I have said it
我已经说过了
Naturally take it seriously
自然会认真对待
This last one
这最后一张
Was it written by a member of your family?
是你家人写的吗？
Exactly
确切地
gentlemen
先生们
These are the four uncles
这是四叔叔
Give you the bonus of being a referee
给你当裁判的红利
Wang was disrespectful.
王氏无礼。
Apologize to your family members on my behalf
代表我向你的家人道歉
Just say that Wang cannot say goodbye in person.
只是说王不能亲自告别。
Hope Haihan
希望海涵
Sir, walk slowly
先生请慢慢走
Return to the three uncles outside the membership
返回会员外的三叔
There are results from Mr. Wang's side
王先生那边有结果了
speak
说话
Mr. Wang said
王先生说
Each of the four characters has its own merits
四个角色各有各的优点
Indistinguishable
难以区分
It's also extremely difficult for him to make a choice
他也很难做出选择
It’s just that since we have to distinguish between high and low
只是既然要分高低
That last piece of writing is so powerful
最后一篇文太给力了
The spirit runs through
精神贯穿
The last word is better
最后一句话更好
Lu Yuanwai
Lu Yuanwai
good calligraphy good calligraphy
好书法 好书法
As expected, Yuan Lu is still very good at writing.
果然，袁璐的文笔还是很不错的。
Brother Lu is still more skilled
鲁哥还是比较熟练的
We are ashamed of ourselves
我们为自己感到羞耻
Ashamed of myself
为自己感到羞耻
transfer transfer
转移 转移
This kind of comparison is really taken advantage of by Lu.
这种对比，实在是被陆利用了。
The only one to blame is Mr. Wang
唯一的罪魁祸首是王先生
Too old-fashioned
太老套了
Nothing to say
无话可说
The teacher cannot set foot in this place of fireworks
老师不能踏足这个烟花之地
The words on the outside of the building must be
建筑物外面的文字必须是
You said it made us
你说它让我们
I had no choice but to write those big characters in the list
我只好把那些大字写在名单上
But who in this county doesn’t know?
但本县谁不知道呢？
Zhao Juren, Brother Zhao
Zhao Juren, Brother Zhao
This regular script has entered the state of enlightenment
此楷书已进入悟道状态
Suffer a loss. Suffer a loss.
遭受损失。遭受损失。
Brother Lu is too modest
鲁哥太谦虚了
four
四
The words are also written
字也写了
High and low are also divided
也有高低之分
The banquet next door was also held
隔壁的宴会也举行了
Shall we have a few drinks?
我们喝几杯好吗？
To add to the fun
为了增添乐趣
Then listen to Siniang
然后听四娘的话
Today we will not return until we are drunk
今天我们不醉不归
Please, please
拜托拜托
please please please
拜托拜托拜托
Uncle, walk slowly
叔叔你慢慢走
Mother Zhao
赵妈妈
Whose little turtle is this?
这是谁的小乌龟？
Lu Zhi, you are teasing me again
陆植你又在逗我
What a powerful bastard boxing
多么厉害的混蛋拳击
Get up and don't interfere with my work
起来吧，别影响我工作
Well, do you think this will bother you?
嗯，你认为这会困扰你吗？
Ghee bubble snails
酥油泡泡蜗牛
Then this is too much trouble
那这个就太麻烦了
I'll take it and show it to you
我会把它拿给你看
I really want to be discovered by Zhao’s mother
好想被赵妈妈发现
Now I have to go outside the back door by myself
现在我必须自己走出后门
Eat alone
一个人吃饭
Then leave two for me
然后留两个给我
Just one will do
只需一个即可
Only the last one left
只剩下最后一张了
Who among us will eat?
我们当中谁会吃饭？
you eat
你吃
I live here in Cuihua Building
我住在翠华楼这里
There are more opportunities to eat than you
吃饭的机会比你多
My son
我的儿子
Your filial piety is enough
有你的孝心就够了
Eat
吃
You give birth to a son who is a turtle
你生了一个儿子，他是一只乌龟
Pretty decent
相当不错
so
所以
Now it’s you who’s giving it to Si Niang when she sleeps out.
现在是你趁四娘睡觉的时候把它送给她了。
When Si Niang sleeps out, she also goes to accompany your family members.
四娘在外面睡觉的时候，也会去陪你的家人。
She was covered
她被覆盖了
We can’t accept other customers either.
我们也不能接受其他客户。
Wait for a few days and my family members will be outside.
等几天，我的家人就会在外面。
When I call Siniang Tiaozi again
当我再叫四娘条子的时候
If you send her to our house
如果你送她来我们家
Let's go out to the city to play
我们去城里玩吧
That's fine
没关系
That
那
What if it's in this other courtyard?
如果是在另一个院子里怎么办？
Just across an alley
就在一条小巷对面
If I don't finish delivering, I have to go back
如果我没有完成交付，我必须回去
Not in this other courtyard
不在另一个院子里
This other courtyard is my family's residence.
另一个院子是我家的住所。
I ate too much wine at your place
我在你那儿喝了太多酒
For overnight stay
过夜住宿
He doesn't want to stay here with you
他不想和你呆在这里
Your family members are really weird.
你的家人真是奇怪。
That's OK
没关系
Let’s go out to the city to play in a few days
过几天我们去城里玩吧
It’s a deal
就这么说定咯
Plum, osmanthus and chrysanthemum cake
梅桂菊花糕
Have a bite
咬一口
no
不
My stomach is very bloated now
我的肚子现在很胀
I'm going to vomit if I eat anymore
我再吃下去就会吐
No wonder you soaked the last conch in ghee
难怪你把最后一个海螺泡在酥油里
Give it to me
把它给我
Open your mouth
张开嘴
Don't eat
不要吃
I feed you
我喂你
Step aside
靠边站
Good words
良言
A good calligrapher
一个好的书法家
Next time when comparing words, compare these three words.
下次比较单词时，就比较这三个单词。
Lu Zhi
Lu Zhi
I'll test you
我来考验你
Do you know why I love comparing words at Tsui Wah House?
你知道我为什么喜欢在翠华楼比较文字吗？
Because it's lively
因为很热闹
You won't understand if you guess it
你猜了你也不会明白
What does Tsui Wah House compare to?
与翠华楼相比如何？
Comparative list book
比较清单书
If this is better than writing in lowercase letters
如果这比用小写字母书写更好
Who can write better than Zhao Juren?
谁能比赵举人写得更好？
This list book
这本清单书
Yuan Wai surpassed Zhao Juren in terms of strength.
论实力，袁外超越了赵举人。
right
正确的
Lu Zhi
Lu Zhi
If you are successful in your studies
如果你学业有成
I'll just spend some money and move around.
我就花点钱，搬家吧。
Give you a membership
给你一个会员资格
Send you to take the exam
送你去参加考试
I want them to see
我想让他们看到
The book boy of our Lu family
我们陆家的书童
You can also take some exams for scholarly examinations.
您还可以参加一些学术考试。
What's so great about this
这有什么了不起的
Yeah
是的
I, Lu Zhi, am exhausted and exhausted.
我陆植，已经筋疲力尽了。
We must also let the members and outsiders fight for this face.
也要让成员和圈外人去争取这个面子。
I'll go there right away
我马上去那儿
Chen Wang
Chen Wang
Tell Yuji
告诉佑二
Open a jar of Jinhua old wine in the evening
晚上开一坛金华老酒
Add two more vegetables
再加两种蔬菜
Roast duck
烤鸭
Silver bream
银鲷
besides
除了
I made that bad crab two days ago
我两天前做了那只糟糕的螃蟹
You should be able to eat it
你应该可以吃它
Lu Zhi
Lu Zhi
Come to the study to have dinner with me in the evening
晚上来书房跟我一起吃晚饭
how do i feel
我感觉如何
Just now Mr. Zhong was speaking sign language with the staff.
刚才钟先生正在和工作人员打手语。
It’s different from the sign language we usually sign with.
它与我们通常用的手语不同。
It's different
这不一样
The sign language that Mr. Zhong usually speaks to us
钟老师平时跟我们说话的手语
They are all general followers
他们都是一般追随者
Called by an outsider
被外人打电话
Added some code words between them
在它们之间添加了一些代码字
You can understand this too
这个你也可以理解
I understand
我明白
You forgot that I lived in the house for the first three years
你忘了我前三年是住在这房子里的
Those who follow are all loyal masters
跟随的都是忠实的主人
Then tell me
然后告诉我
What did they mean just now?
他们刚才是什么意思？
Lord Zhong just now
钟大人刚才
It's about the Cao family's fifty hectares of land
大约是曹家五十公顷的土地
It's the one who broke up into a family fight
是因为一场家庭争吵而分手的人
Make brothers
结交兄弟
Is it the Cao family that used the knife?
用刀的是曹家吗？
yes
是的
Cao’s fifty hectares of land
曹氏五十公顷土地
Upstream of the water source on our land
我们土地上水源的上游
Our family members have always wanted
我们的家人一直想要
But Mr. Cao never wanted to sell it.
但曹先生始终没有想卖掉它。
After that old man Cao dies,
那个曹老头死后，
his three sons
他的三个儿子
So I divided the fifty hectares of land.
于是我把这五十公顷的土地分了。
The eldest brother and the third child still don’t want to sell.
大哥和老三还是不愿意卖。
The second one got a piece in the middle
第二个中间有一块
The smallest and thinnest ground
最小、最薄的地面
I bought it at a high price from a member of the Communist Party of China.
我从一个共产党员那里花高价买的。
But after Yuanwai bought the land, he never planted it.
但员外买下这块地后，就再也没有种过。
A year of drought
一年干旱
I just put some new straw from that year in the ground
我只是把当年的新稻草埋在地里
This is not
这不是
This year, bagworms broke out in both fields.
今年，这两个田地都爆发了结叶虫。
Snow everywhere
到处都是雪
No harvest
没有收获
Our family members will buy those two pieces of land at a low price.
我们家里人会低价买下这两块地。
Bought it
买了它
The eldest and third son of the Cao family
曹家长子、三子
He should be in the study at the moment
他现在应该在书房里
Signed and pledged?
签署并承诺？
so
所以
This leafworm was released in our house
这只叶虫被释放到我们家
No one can say that it was released by our family.
谁也不能说是我们家放出来的。
But those farmers know it in their hearts
但那些农民心里都清楚
In the straw stalks of the year
当年的秸秆里
Seeds thrown by pests
害虫抛出的种子
It seems like this
好像是这样的
This guy is so scheming
这家伙太有心机了
This may not be the scheming of outsiders.
这或许不是外人的心机。
It should be Mr. Zhong’s
应该是钟先生的
The fish ran away
鱼跑掉了
What are you thinking about?
你在想什么？
Zhongye
Zhongye
I have something to tell you
我有件事要告诉你
I found Mr. Wang from the private school
我找到了私塾的王老师
a secret
一个秘密
That day I put the inkstone
那天我把砚台
Lost it in Wu Lei Zhai
丢在武磊斋
I'll go back and get it
我会回去拿它
so many years
这么多年
You still haven't let me go
你还是没有放开我
You came again last night
昨晚你又来了
Today I will ask him to beat him harder.
今天我就请他狠狠地打他。
If it makes trouble again
如果再惹麻烦的话
I have no choice but to
我别无选择，只能
Moved you somewhere else
把你搬到别的地方了
if you promise me
如果你答应我
A gust of wind blew
一阵风吹过
Let the copper bell on the eaves ring a few times
让屋檐上的铜铃响几声
I won’t touch you anymore
我不会再碰你了
You little monkey have always been like this
你这个小猴子一直都是这样的
Good advice but not listening
很好的建议，但不听
If you don't respond to me today
如果你今天没有回复我
I will do what I say
我会按我所说的去做
Okay, okay, okay
好吧好吧好吧
Not moving anymore
不再动了
I can't move you anymore
我再也无法感动你
Okay, okay
好吧好吧
please please please
拜托拜托拜托
But don't make trouble anymore
但别再惹麻烦了
Let's not offend the river.
我们不要冒犯河流。
It will be fifteen in a few days
再过几天就十五了
I'll come to sacrifice you again
我会再次来牺牲你
This is not what children should know
这不是孩子应该知道的
Don't tell others
不要告诉别人
I know Mr. Zhong
我认识钟先生
I'm only talking to you about this matter
我只是和你谈论这件事
Don't worry about me because I'm mute
别担心我，因为我是哑巴
Not because you are mute
不是因为你哑巴
Because you are the best person to me in the entire Lu family
因为你是整个陆家对我最好的人
You will never harm me
你永远不会伤害我
know other people's secrets
知道别人的秘密
Danger
危险
I know Mr. Zhong
我认识钟先生
I don't know why
我不知道为什么
It's like it's something other people don't want people to know
就好像这是别人不想让别人知道的事情
Everyone will be bumped into by me
大家都会被我撞到
You are a kid and lovable
你是个孩子又可爱
Others are not wary of you
别人对你没有戒心
I also know how you became mute
我也知道你是怎么变成哑巴的
how did you know
你怎么知道
You were abused by your stepmother when you were a child
你小时候被继母虐待过
No food to eat
没有食物吃
Just go to the kitchen and steal the leftovers to eat
就去厨房偷剩菜吃
Caught by stepmother
被继母抓住
I gave you some salt brine for tofu.
我给了你一些做豆腐的盐水。
Then your throat is burned out
然后你的喉咙就被烧坏了
A member of staff told you
一位工作人员告诉你
I say it again
我再说一遍
In the Lu family
在陆家
secret danger
秘密危险
Danger
危险
I know Mr. Zhong
我认识钟先生
I remember
我记得
Walk
走
You first go to the ruined temple outside the south gate and wait for me.
你先去南门外的破庙里等我。
I'm going to do something
我要做点什么
I'll find you soon
我很快就会找到你
What else can happen to you?
你还能发生什么？
Anyway, something happened
无论如何，有事发生了
Just go wait for me for a while
你去等我一会儿吧
You hurry up
你快点
Cold catcher
冷捕手
hold
抓住
Thank you Leng Captou
谢谢你冷卡普图
It's actually the cold catcher
其实它是驱寒剂
Lu Zhi
Lu Zhi
look
看
kingfisher
翠鸟
How did you do this with your hands?
你是如何用手做到这一点的？
fine
美好的
Two days ago, I went to Hongyu's room to steal snacks.
前两天，我去红宇房间偷零食。
She has a bad temper
她脾气不好
Just prick me with a needle
就用针扎我一下
You know she has a bad temper
你知道她脾气不好
And went to steal her snacks
还去偷她的零食
I stole her just because I knew it.
我偷了她只是因为我知道这一点。
Don't steal if someone has a good temperament
脾气好就不要偷窃
Why
为什么
Shouldn’t I steal someone with a good temperament?
难道我不应该去偷一个气质好的人吗？
Even if they find out
即使他们发现了
I won't do anything to you
我不会对你做任何事
People with good temperaments will be stolen from them
脾气好的人会被抢走
Then wouldn’t this world be the opposite?
那么这个世界岂不是相反了？
But this world is inherently the opposite.
但这个世界本质上是相反的。
Can you still change this world?
你还能改变这个世界吗？
I can't change it
我无法改变它
But here my little baby
但在这里我的小宝贝
If you have a good temperament, you can't steal.
如果你的脾气好，你就不会偷窃。
Is the fourth lady considered to have a good temperament?
四小姐也算是气质不错吧？
Si Niang is the most temperamental.
四娘是最有气质的。
Originally, the girls went to sleep out in the house
原本，女孩们去屋外睡觉
Sui Laosan should be the one delivering them all.
隋老三应该是把他们全部送走的人。
But Si Niang knows that I want to sneak out and play
但四娘知道我想偷偷溜出去玩
Just let me deliver it
让我来送吧
But others say the bitch is ruthless
但也有人说这个婊子很无情
Mostly ruthless
大多是无情的
But only Si Niang is different
但只有四娘不一样
What's the difference
有什么不同
She is a kind and kind person
她是一个善良又善良的人
Sending you out to play is considered affectionate and righteous.
送你出去玩，算是有情有义。
no
不
Si Niang is kind to everyone
四娘对谁都好
Good for everyone
对每个人都有好处
It's not necessarily sentimental.
这不一定是感性的。
At most, he is kind to others
最多就是对别人好一点
Anyway, I don’t believe they can have any friendship.
无论如何，我不相信他们能有什么友谊。
Si Niang is affectionate and righteous
四娘有情有义
To whom
给谁
You are still a member of my family
你仍然是我家庭的一员
Si Niang is angry with Leng Capt.
四娘对冷队长生气了。
Siniang has something to do with Leng Captou
四娘和冷卡头有关系
Lu Zhi
Lu Zhi
I beg you
我求求你
Don't tell anyone
不要告诉任何人
What's my grandfather's temper like?
我爷爷的脾气怎么样？
The girl he kept
他养的那个女孩
I can't accept any more customers.
我不能再接受更多的顾客了。
If he knew about this
如果他知道这件事
Siniang will be in bad luck even if she catches her head coldly.
四娘冷落了她的头，也会倒霉的。
I beg you
我求求你
You must never tell your family members
您绝不能告诉您的家人
You get up first
你先起来
You can't trust your brother so much
你不能这么信任你的兄弟
I guarantee it directly
我直接保证
Never tell anyone about this matter
永远不要告诉任何人这件事
Chen Wang
Chen Wang
What are you doing, young master?
少爷你在做什么？
Is your mother feeling better recently?
你妈妈最近感觉好些了吗？
My mother's business
我妈妈的生意
I have to thank you even more, Mr. Qian
更要感谢你，钱先生
I feel much better since taking the medicine
服药后我感觉好多了
Don't worry, Master Qian
钱老师放心吧
I will definitely give you the money for the medicine.
药钱我一定会给你。
Okay, okay
好吧好吧
I ask you
我问你
Is it your turn to be on duty today?
今天轮到你值班吗？
yes
是的
Is such that
是这样的吗
I met a fortune teller on the street the day before yesterday
前天我在街上遇见了一个算命先生
He just said that I am the 16th of this month
他只是说我这个月16号
There will be a bloody disaster
将会有一场血腥的灾难
Master Qian, please don’t believe that.
钱老师，请不要相信。
Is that a trap for you?
这对你来说是一个陷阱吗？
I know this
我知道这个
So I didn’t ask him to crack it either.
所以我也没有要求他破解。
It’s just that I’ve been feeling uneasy these past few days.
只是这几天心里一直有些不安。
Tomorrow is sixteen
明天十六号
It happens to be my turn to stay on duty
正好轮到我继续值班
I feel a little taboo about this
我对此感到有点禁忌
How about we switch shifts?
我们换班怎么样？
I'll stay up late for you today
今天我会为你熬夜
Siniang
Siniang
Is the old beast asleep?
老畜生睡着了吗？
Drank too much
喝太多了
Sleeping like a dead man
睡得像死人一样
good
好的
Siniang
Siniang
Miss me so much
非常想念我
What's wrong
怎么了
fine
美好的
Come on
快点
Go sit over there
去那边坐坐
Slower
慢点
sit down
坐下
Siniang
Siniang
Is it that old beast?
是那个老畜生吗？
He hurt you again
他又伤害你了
It's a bit lighter today
今天有点轻
Neither am I. He is in Tsui Wah House
我也不是，他在翠华楼
The first girl in the bag
第一个包里的女孩
The first few
前几个
Who knows where they all went?
谁知道他们都去了哪里？
You can’t see people alive, you can’t see corpses even when they’re dead.
活着的人看不见，死了也看不见尸体。
What sound?
什么声音？
It's a wild cat, right?
这是一只野猫，对吗？
Siniang
Siniang
Look at how beautiful the moon is tonight
看看今晚的月亮多美丽
yes
是的
do not move
不要动
If you move again I will strangle you to death.
你再动我就掐死你。
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Siniang
Siniang
give me your handkerchief and belt
把你的手帕和皮带给我
What to do next
接下来做什么
I get him away
我把他带走
You go back first
你先回去吧
Walk
走
don't hurt him
别伤害他
who
WHO
do not move
不要动
It’s me, Qu Tianming
是我曲天明
cold head
冷头
Who do I think I am?
我以为我是谁？
What are you doing in the middle of the night?
大半夜的你在做什么？
Just caught a thief
刚抓到小偷
Little thief
小贼
Thank you for your hard work, Lengtou.
谢谢你的辛苦，冷头。
That
那
I'll accompany you back to the Yamen
我陪你回衙门
No more work
没有更多的工作
What can a little thief do to me?
一个小贼能对我做什么？
Just go ahead and make your update.
继续进行更新即可。
No need
不需要
No
不
gone
消失了
We've arrived
我们到了
You sneaked out from Lu's house and committed theft
你从卢家偷偷溜出来，犯了盗窃罪
I caught it
我抓住了它
On the way to escort you back
正在送你回去的路上
Unexpectedly, halfway
没想到，半途而废
Met the watchman Qu Tianming
Met the watchman Qu Tianming
He can be a witness
他可以成为证人
and after
之后
You resisted arrest and ran away
你拒捕并逃跑
We two got stuck together
我们两个粘在一起了
Unexpectedly, I accidentally
没想到一不小心
your head hits the wall
你的头撞到了墙上
Cold catcher
冷捕手
let me help you
我来帮你
Do you want to run away again?
你还想再逃跑吗？
Why are you back again?
你怎么又回来了？
I forgot to give you the lantern just now
我刚才忘记给你灯笼了
I finally got a chance when I was young
年轻的时候终于有机会了
Can help catch the thief
可以帮助抓小偷
This can be regarded as a small achievement, right?
这也算是一个小小的成就吧？
Thank you for your help
感谢您的帮助
where where
哪里哪里
I was negligent just now
刚才我疏忽了
I didn't expect this little thief to be very cunning and naughty.
没想到这个小贼非常狡猾，而且调皮。
cold head
冷头
I'll take you back to the Yamen
我送你回衙门
At least it can give you a light
至少可以给你一盏灯
No need, no need
不需要，不需要
You go back
你回去吧
It doesn't matter
没关系
cold head
冷头
This is a small matter
这是一件小事
stand up
起来
Follow me back to the Yamen
随我回衙门
Walk
走
hurry up
赶快
It's much easier to do it here
在这里做起来更容易
I can interrogate you
我可以审问你
You will inevitably be punished
你将不可避免地受到惩罚
You can survive the punishment but lose your life
你可以逃脱惩罚，但却失去生命
No one will find it strange
没有人会觉得奇怪
i can help you
我可以帮你
I can help you and Siniang
我可以帮助你和四娘
I can even pretend to pass on the master's words
我什至可以假装传授师父的话
Invite Si Niang out for a tryst with you
邀四娘出来幽会
do not worry
不用担心
My husband’s account with Tsui Wah House
我丈夫在翠华楼的户口
Half a year
半年
And it's silver-wrapped
而且是银色包裹的
More than once or twice a month
每月一次或两次以上
No one can find out
没有人能查出
You are trying to survive now
你现在正在努力生存
You really dare to say anything.
你真是什么都敢说啊。
I am the book boy of the Lu family
我是陆家书童
Even if you catch me sneaking around
就算你发现我偷偷摸摸
You won’t tell my master
你不会告诉我的主人
Self-inflicted punishment will cost me my life
自我惩罚会让我付出生命的代价
What is my master’s temperament?
我的主人是什么性格？
What kind of person is he?
他是一个什么样的人？
How could he let go of you?
他怎么可能放过你？
And you can prove it with just one sentence
而且只需一句话就能证明
Did you catch me outside Lu's house?
你在卢家外面遇见我了吗？
If I have evidence to prove
如果我有证据证明
You abducted me from Lu's house?
你把我从陆家拐走了？
what evidence
什么证据
It’s almost five days now, right?
现在已经快五天了吧？
It was my turn to stay on duty last night
昨晚轮到我值班了
Logically speaking
按理说
I should have found a housekeeper by now
我现在应该找个管家了
Report handed in
报告已交
He's probably looking for me everywhere now
他现在可能正在到处找我
you kill me now
你现在杀了我
Then rush to the Lu family to destroy the evidence.
然后赶去陆家销毁证据。
It's too late
太晚了
I ask you what evidence
我问你什么证据
what evidence
什么证据
lantern
灯笼
My night lantern
我的夜灯
Still on the edge of the Taihu Stone in the garden
还在花园里的太湖石边上
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
The people from Lu Zhai looked for me but couldn't find them.
陆寨的人找我，却没有找到。
But I found the lantern I used for night duty
但我找到了我夜班用的灯笼
Fall there
跌倒那里
What would they guess?
他们会猜到什么？
Even if I go out to steal
就算出去偷东西
And why are you throwing the lantern there?
你为什么要把灯笼扔在那里？
And I happened to die in your hands
而我却偏偏死在你手里
you say
你说
Where did you catch me?
你在哪里抓到我的？
besides
除了
The master was drunk last night
主人昨晚喝醉了
Siniang stayed there for the night
四娘在那里过夜
I disappeared outside her door
我消失在她门外
If she said she didn't even hear the slightest movement
如果她说她连一丝动静都没有听到
How can we not make people suspicious?
怎样才能不让人怀疑呢？
You don't want to drag her into this, do you?
你不想把她也拖进去吧？
You naughty slave
你这个顽皮的奴隶
Don't mention her
别提她
Cold catcher
冷捕手
Why do you need to kill me?
为什么你需要杀了我？
I told you I would help you and Siniang
我说过我会帮助你和四娘的
stand up
起来
sit here
在这里坐
I want to hear it
我想听
why do you want to help us
你为什么想帮助我们
My hands are numb
我的手已经麻木了
Can you help me untie it first?
你能先帮我解开吗？
Cold catcher
冷捕手
Although I have never had any dealings with you
虽然我从来没有和你有过任何来往
But you were kind to me
但你对我很好
be kind to you
善待你
I was born a little beggar
我生来就是一个小乞丐
He became a book boy after being taken in by the police
被警察收留后，他成了一名书童
Six years ago when I was begging for food
六年前，当我乞讨食物时
Zhao Juren's housekeeper passed by on horseback
赵举人管家骑马路过
I accidentally blocked his way
我不小心挡住了他的路
He is about to step on his horse
他正要跨上马
It was you who held the reins
是你掌控了缰绳
The matter was resolved with good words and persuasion.
经过一番好言和劝说，事情就解决了。
without you
没有你
I've long been dead
我已经死了很久了
six years ago
六年前
Why don't I remember this?
为什么我不记得这个了？
This is a small thing for you
这对你来说是一件小事
Of course you won't remember
你当然不会记得
But this is a great favor to me
但这对我来说是一个很大的恩惠
You didn't make this up, did you?
这不是你编造的，是吗？
I have another reason to help you
我还有另一个理由来帮助你
what reason
什么原因
I'm afraid you'll laugh at me if I say it.
我怕我说出来你会笑我。
Actually it's me
其实是我
I have always admired Si Niang very much
我一直很崇拜四娘
That's why I'm hiding in the backyard today
这就是我今天躲在后院的原因
This matter involves Siniang
这件事涉及四娘
anyway
反正
I won't do anything bad to her
我不会对她做任何坏事
Say it again
再说一遍
Who do you say you admire?
你说你欣赏谁？
whom to admire
欣赏谁
Siniang
Siniang
You admire Lin Siniang
You admire Lin Siniang
Then you should hate me
那你就该恨我
Why should I hate you
我为什么要恨你
You admire Lin Siniang
You admire Lin Siniang
I have an affair with her
我和她有染
Shouldn't you hate me?
你不应该恨我吗？
As you say
正如你所说
I should hate you
我应该恨你
Or should I hate my family members?
或者我应该恨我的家人吗？
Whether it's killing or releasing
无论是杀戮还是释放
We all have to make a decision quickly.
我们都必须迅速做出决定。
Why do I still not believe you?
为什么我还是不相信你？
If you let me go
如果你让我走
I might complain to my family members
我可能会向我的家人抱怨
But maybe not
但也许不是
But if you kill me
但如果你杀了我
It will definitely cause trouble
肯定会带来麻烦
Why don't you throw a coin?
为什么不扔硬币呢？
Toss a coin
抛硬币
If the roll comes up heads, let me go.
如果骰子正面朝上，就放我走。
What if the roll comes tails?
如果卷反了怎么办？
Then you'll be in trouble
那么你就会有麻烦了
It's easy to deal with me
对付我很容易
It's too difficult to explain
太难解释了
Siniang
Siniang
Walk
走